Robert J. Nixon

21 Grebe Road, Bicester | 07557023792 | robert@robertnixon.net

Experience

Bicester Town Council

Councillor • May 2019 - Present

Green Party councillor representing Bicester East

Sophos

Software Engineer • July 2019 - September 2019

Global Academy Jobs

Junior Web Developer • April 2018 - June 2019

Key Responsibilities

 Applying technical knowledge to a social enterprise project called The Global Academy. Providing technical knowledge to the decision making process and developing features required for the project website

theglobalacademy.ac

- Writing and maintaining Python scripts used to retrieve job advertisements from client's jobs boards and import them into the GAJobs website ready for moderation.
- Deploying these Python scripts onto a virtual machine running on MS Azure.
- Editing and uploading job advertisements to Global Academy Jobs' academic jobs board.

Technologies Used

Python, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Git Version Control, Drupal, MS Azure

Summary

I joined Global Academy Jobs at the end of my first year of university. After 1 month I was offered a 10 week full time internship part funded by Santander's Universities SME internship scheme. After this I've continued completing various technical tasks whilst progressing with my university studies.

Develop 1 Ltd

Work Experience Student • July 2016

I joined Develop 1 for a week of work experience after finishing my AS Levels. Whilst there I worked on managing and maintaining SQL databases with MS server management studio. I also learned about the admin side of running a small business, for example I was put in change of calculating the expenses for the company for the past year.

Education

Oxford Brookes University

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science • 2017 — 2020

Current GPA = 4.0

Wheatley Park School

A-Levels • 2015 — 2017

Grade A Mathematics, Grade B Computer Science, Grade C Physics, Grade C AS Further Mathematics and Grade A Level 3 EPQ.

The Cooper School

GCSEs • 2010 - 2015

11 GCSEs grades A* - B including A grades in Mathematics and B grades in English

Volunteer Experience

North Oxfordshire Green Party

Various Roles • 2015 — Present

Chair (2018 - Present): - I'm responsible for the overall running of the branch. This includes organising and chairing meetings, helping to oversee the direction of the party locally and running events.

Web Developer (2015 - Present): - Before I joined the Green Party my local branch had no website and were reliant of Facebook and Twitter for their online presence. I created a website for them and have continued the update and adapt it as requirements change.

Membership Secretary (2017 - Present): - I manage the branch membership records. This includes using CiviCRM and making sure that members are informed about news and upcoming events.

Election Agent (2018 - Present): - Responsibilities include recruiting and supporting Green Party election candidates in the Cherwell district, ensuring all paperwork related to Green Party candidates standing in elections in the Cherwell district is submitted to the council on time and correctly, understanding changes to election law and helping candidates understand these changes and ensuring that volunteers and candidates know what they need to do at the counting of votes.

South East Young Greens

Elections officer • 2019 - Present

The Green Party of England and Wales

Party Member • 2015 — Present

Skills

Political campaigning

Local election campaign management, volunteers coordination, fundraising, public speaking.

Languages and Software Development Tools

Python, Java, C, C++, HTML, Markdown, LaTeX, CSS, JavaScript, Git Version Control, NetBeans, PyCharm, Android Studio, Visual Studio Code

Operating Systems

Linux/Unix, Windows, MacOS

Other Software Tools

GIMP, Kdenlive, LibreOffice, MS Office, Google Drive

Social Links

- Github: https://github.com/robnixon
- **Twitter**: http://twitter.com/_robertjnixon
- Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/the.robert.j.nixon
- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/robertjosephnixon/
- Website: https://robertnixon.net